Deepak Hariharan

Senior Software Developer seeking roles In Application Development, Project Management, Application Maintenance, Application Support, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, ZigBee, Powerbuilder, Visual Basic . Net, C#, J2EE, Arduino, PHP, Oracle, Sybase

- Current Designation: Senior Software Developer -Software Development
- Current Company: Incubit Global Business Services
- Current Location: Gurgaon
- Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Mumbai, Ernakulam
- Functional Area: IT Software Application Programming / Maintenance
- Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead
- Industry: IT-Software/Software Services
- Marital Status: Married
- Total Experience: 22 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
- Notice Period: 15 Days or less
- Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]
- Key Skills: Senior Software Developer, Tech Lead, Application Development, Project Management, Application Maintenance, Application Support, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, ZigBee, Powerbuilder, Visual Basic . Net, C#, J2EE, Arduino, PHP, Oracle, Sybase

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 4a25a0bd213be31268Last Active: 18-Sep-20Last Modified: 18-Sep-20

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Exposed to working across domains of Stock and share Market (Bombay Stock Exchange), financial domain (National Finance Company, Sultanate of Oman, Transportation System (Cubic Transportation System, United Kingdom), Supply chain management (APTEC LLC, Dubai), Manufacturing Domain (Kingdom of Cambodia), Payroll Information System (Kingdom of Saudi Arabia).

Skilled in managing research and development of new modules and introduce new technology into the project leading to enhanced project efficiency and quality.

High mentoring ability with excellent communication and team management skills. A person with analytical mindset to cater to exigencies.

Work Experience

•

Incubit Global Business Services as Senior Software Developer -Software Development

Jan 2018 to Till Date

Key Responsibilities:

Manage software development projects, online / post go-live support and conduct system integration testing for client DB Schenker India Private Limited.

Interact with client for collating and evaluating requirements to align with project deliverables. Enhance client satisfaction by effectively resolving issues and rendering superior quality service.

Maintain updated knowledge of technological advancements in field of operations to implement the same across assigned project phases.

Highlight critical technical issues to the senior management and other stakeholders for implementing effective remedial measures.

Technology used: SQL Server 2005, PowerBuilder 2017 R3 Appean, C#, ZigBee, Visual C++

•

Injazat Information Technology as Programmer

Mar 2016 to Oct 2017

Key Responsibilities:

Involved in setting up the Payroll Information System followed by identification and resolution of bugs.

Rendered post implementation support to the client and incorporated changes based on evaluated change requests.

Guided clients in effectively and adequately maintaining back up of critical data to cater to various exigencies.

Technology used: SQL Server 2005, PowerBuilder 12.0, C#

•

Agile Financial Technologies as Consultant

Jul 2010 to Apr 2016

Key Responsibilities:

Involved in setting up Register and Transfer as well as migrating database from SQL Server to Oracle for United Bank of Africa - Register and Transfer.

Developed and implemented systems based on Agile methodologies and worked on technologies like Oracle 11g, PowerBuilder 11.0,C#.

^ Back to Top

Education

- UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Mahatma Gandhi University (MGU) in 1994
- PG: MCA (Computers) from Madras University, Chennai in 1997

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

AppeonPowerbuilder 2017, Visual Basic 6.0

0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Visual C++5.0,.Net,C#

J2EE,ESP32 IoT,Arduino,I2C

SQL Server 2000, Oracle 8.0, Sybase 12

SCO UNIX, Windows NT 4.0/ NT Terminal

Novell 4.0

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

English Expert

Hindi Expert

Malayalam